<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-01T18:03:19+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">octofidotcom</title><subtitle>Website for OctoFi: Decentralized Finance Tentacles. Hosted on Github Pages.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why You Can’t Find Our Community On This Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/community" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Can't Find Our Community On This Website" /><published>2020-08-30T10:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-30T10:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/community</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/community">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR - If it ain’t organic, it ain’t community.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been around crypto long enough to know a thing or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may already be aware that between us we’ve got eight limbs and eight years experience. We bring salt and pepper to the table. And tentacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s a few observations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moderating a community is time intensive, distracting, and counterproductive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many teams start their ‘community’ themselves and censor its participants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most projects deploy their ‘blog’ to a piece of shit walled garden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the above points sound very open, transparent, or decentralized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regarding platforms where observations were made:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discord&lt;/strong&gt; is essentially a feature-rich chat room for gamers and yet seems to be used for a lot of governance discussions. Quite cumbersome considering it doesn’t even have nested replies and anything worth reading is gone in a flash. There’s also loads of bots that interfere with proceedings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Telegram Groups&lt;/strong&gt; get overrun by spammers and bots, and the majority of time spent is on swinging the ban hammer around. At least it has nested replies, but without the ability to host channels and break up the discussions, groups are analagous to troll boxes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discourse&lt;/strong&gt; is much the same as Discord, but better suited to governance, as its intended purpose is for running a forum. Seems a reasonable choice for hosting discussions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reddit&lt;/strong&gt; is the power hungry moderator’s censorship paradise. Most crypto communities have far exceeded their use-by-dates with the exception of a few smaller ones.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium&lt;/strong&gt; may as well be a piece of dogshit on the bottom of the prison-issue canvas slip-ons awaiting Craig Wright’s arrival. They hold content ransom behind paywalls and are centralized AF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you can deploy smart contracts to Ethereum then surely you can deploy a Jekyll-powered, RSS-enabled blog to GitHub Pages (for FREE) and write some Markdown, ffs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for our sharing of these thoughts is that the community itself can choose to congregate wherever they see fit. We won’t be moderating, or creating any communities, but are more than happy to join if you would like to create and moderate your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything we do is open source (this website included) and building is our priority. That’s why we aren’t wasting our time with so-called “community-management” and if there is to be a “community” it may as well be grass roots certified organic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On that note, here’s everything you should be aware of:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/octofi&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for progress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for updates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dao.octo.fi&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aragon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything we have to say will hit the blog first and is shared to Twitter, our Telegram Channel, and our mailing list. You can find all those &lt;a href=&quot;#get-updates&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro tip: our mailing list is hooked up to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://octo.fi/feed.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; and bonding curve commences 14 September 2020 at 00:00 UTC at &lt;a href=&quot;https://buy.octo.fi&quot;&gt;buy.octo.fi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">TL;DR - If it ain’t organic, it ain’t community.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project Reserve for Transparent Improvement Funding</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/project-reserve" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project Reserve for Transparent Improvement Funding" /><published>2020-08-28T10:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-28T10:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/project-reserve</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/project-reserve">&lt;p&gt;Openness and transparency are central to OctoFi’s mission in the delivery of decentralized finance &lt;s&gt;oracles&lt;/s&gt; tentacles. Innovation will be supported by a dedicated fund of governance tokens, or a project reserve, that shall be delegated to foster progress and developments within the DeFi ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a truly community focused initiative, incentives are aligned to the benefit of stakeholders and the long term viability of the project itself. The OctoFi reserve is designed with two main objectives in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Autonomist:&lt;/strong&gt; within the ecosystem, &lt;a href=&quot;https://octo.fi/blog/gov-token-mech&quot;&gt;governance token mechanisms&lt;/a&gt; enable DAO participants to leverage Aragon in such a way that complete autonomy is achievable, and accelerated for the greater good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Innovator:&lt;/strong&gt; project reserve funding shall be disbursed through the Octagon, a concept for community governed support of transparent (and accountable) contributions to open data initiatives within decentralized finance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-reserve-structure&quot;&gt;Project reserve structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these objectives concerning accelerating autonomy and fostering innovation in mind, OctoFi has allocated 275,000 OCTO to the project reserve — representing 34.375% of the total supply of 800k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community-driven deployment of funds are intended to incentivise the open-source development of additional dapps, and supporting infrastructure for truly open and transparent data &lt;s&gt;oracles&lt;/s&gt; tentacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-reserve-governance&quot;&gt;Project reserve governance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stakeholders are empowered to propose and vote on governance matters for the decentralized autonomous organization (DAO) deployed to the Aragon platform. The allocation and disbursement of funds relating to the project reserve is decided on by OCTO governance token holders themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We understand the importance of effectively and efficiently managing these decisions and are committed to ensuring the best possible transition between launch and complete decentralization of project governance. Further details will be provided in the near future regarding early stage proposals and instructions for submission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-octagon&quot;&gt;The Octagon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although in its early stages of development, the Octagon concept is based loosely on the ‘lab’ model, but tailored to community governance and incentives. While OctoFi as an ecosystem is intended to be fully autonomous, it’s important that stakeholders are met with the resources required to actually support innovation. That is, to incentivise the adoption of scalable &lt;s&gt;oracle&lt;/s&gt; tentacle infrastructure, both crowd sourced and crowd supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OctoFi ecosystem is intended to provide the foundation for development of new data-driven applications, as well as the improvement of those already in operation. It is critical that the project reserve is managed with the best interests of the broader DeFi community in mind, as it is a collaborative approach, and by no means monopoly, that will enable the uprooting of legacy financial systems in favor of those which are decentralized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-octagon-structure&quot;&gt;The Octagon structure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the finer details of how the Octagon shall operate are essentially an upcoming governance decision, the basics are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A think tank of thought leaders&lt;/strong&gt; focused on data and its utilisation throughout the DeFi space, including those well-versed in exchange, lending, trading, derivatives, insurance, interoperability, predictive technologies (such as AI/ML), and data privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A cohort of researchers and technologists&lt;/strong&gt; focused on the advancement of open-source contributions to R&amp;amp;D for infrastructure and applications that showcase the importance of an unambiguous data economy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A community of idealists&lt;/strong&gt; who are dedicated to protecting the integrity of the ecosystem by assembling to share ideas, proposals, criticisms, general knowledge, and host meaningful discussions that help shape OctoFi strategically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-ahead&quot;&gt;Looking ahead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While OCTO holders are the ones granted rights to vote on project governance, the Octagon is intended to be open to all contributors, even those who are not stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their contributions are obviously limited in that they will not hold voting rights, but the community nature of the system is best aligned with open-source software practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future posts we will deep dive into the governance platform at &lt;a href=&quot;https://dao.octo.fi&quot;&gt;dao.octo.fi&lt;/a&gt; in order to better demonstrate its functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, the team is focused on Octoken, the bonding curve commencing on 14 September 2020 at 00:00 UTC at &lt;a href=&quot;https://buy.octo.fi&quot;&gt;buy.octo.fi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Openness and transparency are central to OctoFi’s mission in the delivery of decentralized finance oracles tentacles. Innovation will be supported by a dedicated fund of governance tokens, or a project reserve, that shall be delegated to foster progress and developments within the DeFi ecosystem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Interest Pool for Earning Yield with Octokens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/interest-pool" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interest Pool for Earning Yield with Octokens" /><published>2020-08-25T10:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-25T10:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/interest-pool</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/interest-pool">&lt;p&gt;OctoFi is dedicated to achieving the best possible distribution of OCTO governance tokens among holders. With that commitment we are thrilled to announce &lt;a href=&quot;/project/aquafarm&quot;&gt;Aquafarm&lt;/a&gt;, our interest (and airdrop) program providing an attractive incentive scheme for investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both private and public sale participants will be able to assign tokens to our interest yielding smart contract, to earn additional OCTO for 3, 6, and 12 month runtimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interest-program-overview&quot;&gt;Interest program overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 200,000 OCTO split equally between interest yielding contract and airdrop, has been allocated to the interest program. Private sale investors cannot assign their Octokens early, and are afforded the same interest program access as public participants — the interface will be made available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://earn.octo.fi&quot;&gt;earn.octo.fi&lt;/a&gt; only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An additional bonus yield is rewarded to supporters who take part in the first batch, scaled accordingly to their nominated runtime. Depending on the demand shown for the interest program, further bonus schemes may be opened, pending the relevant discussions required to revise the conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon completion of the bonding curve sale, the interest program launch can be expected soon after. Our blog will be used as the first instance for all official announcements, then immediately dispersed across our twitter, telegram, and mailing list in accordance with UTC timezone scheduling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interest-program-details&quot;&gt;Interest program details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve chosen to keep the program simple with measures to prevent any means by which private investors would have an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Runtime&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Interest rate p.a.&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Batch 001 bonus p.a.&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Total accrual&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 months&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.5%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12.5% p.a.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6 months&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20% p.a.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12 months&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;22%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;32% p.a.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As detailed in the above table, the yield for respective interest program runtimes are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three (3) months: 10% per annum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Six (6) months: 15% per annum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twelve (12) months: 22% per annum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For investors participating in the first batch of the interest program, bonus yield as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three (3) months: bonus 2.5% per annum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Six (6) months: bonus 5% per annum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twelve (12) months: bonus 10% per annum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better incentivize mid to long term runtimes, the 200,000 OCTO allocation is split equally between the standard interest program, and airdrops disbursed to addresses completing at least six (6) months of runtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100,000 for interest program yield payments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100,000 for interest program airdrop payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airdrops are specified as 100 OCTO to each address that successfully completes six (6) months runtime of the interest program — obviously limited to the first 1,000 holders to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interest-program-future&quot;&gt;Interest program future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional yield bearing integrations shall be made pending community decisions made. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://earn.octo.fi&quot;&gt;earn.octo.fi&lt;/a&gt; interface is intended to be used to provide maximum value to Octonauts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All official announcements will be made on our blog first and foremost. Following completion of the bonding curve, we will announce official commencement for the interest program. The program will run perpetually until the interest program allocation is exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the leadup to the launch of the interest program we will publish official tutorials and user guides on the blog for those interested in participating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;subtitle&quot; id=&quot;timer&quot;&gt;Bonding curve in...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full details of the Octoken bonding curve distribution and decentralized exchange allocation of the OCTO governance token are &lt;a href=&quot;/project/token&quot;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, come and wrap your tenties around our octoMemes on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/octofinance&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OctoFi is dedicated to achieving the best possible distribution of OCTO governance tokens among holders. With that commitment we are thrilled to announce Aquafarm, our interest (and airdrop) program providing an attractive incentive scheme for investors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bonding Curve Sale Details for OCTO Governance Token</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/bond-curve-sale" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bonding Curve Sale Details for OCTO Governance Token" /><published>2020-08-22T10:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-22T10:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/bond-curve-sale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/bond-curve-sale">&lt;p class=&quot;subtitle&quot; id=&quot;timer&quot;&gt;Bonding curve in...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OctoFi will distribute the OCTO governance token through the Octoken project, a bonding curve distribution starting 14 September 2020 at 00:00 UTC. We welcome all those who support the development of the DeFi ecosystem and a total of 125,000 tokens are being made available to participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-bonding-curve-offering&quot;&gt;What is a bonding curve offering?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/coinmonks/token-bonding-curves-explained-7a9332198e0e&quot;&gt;Bonding curves are smart contracts&lt;/a&gt; designed to provide tokens with their own market by creating buy and sell functions. Token prices increase and decrease as they are bought and sold from the contract respectively. The number of tokens on the market, and the average price of each token per transfer batch, are the characteristics that determine a trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers gain control over the project and team, to a degree, thanks to the contract autonomously creating a market and remaining 100% collateralized at all times. Bonding curve participants can essentially sell tokens back at any time over a uniswap marketplace pair, for a fair and transparent means of distributing governance rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“…risks are minimised, requiring both the developer and the vote to be compromised to cause any real damage.” — &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/t/explanation-of-daicos/465&quot;&gt;Vitalik Buterin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By distributing governance in such a way, token bonding curves provide fairness and transparency. They are a sustainable way of striking a balance between the team and project supporters, to hold everyone accountable in the best interests of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-octoken-bonding-curve-offering&quot;&gt;The Octoken bonding curve offering&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is critical to the project that early adopters are incentivized to foster a supportive environment and as such, longevity for the governance token’s utility. The bonding curve distribution method has been chosen as the first method for getting OCTO governance tokens into the hands of public stakeholders. The only prior allocation made is that of 200,000 OCTO among a small strategic cohort to ensure the best possible deployment and transition for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/curve.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the ‘sigmoid bonding curve’ model, OctoFi shall remunerate early supporters for their participation and commitment to DeFi in the broader sense, rather than favoring short term speculators. As explained in our governance mechanisms post, the Octoken project is the first mechanism through which we are decentralizing governance of OctoFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Batch&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Allocation&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Price (USDC)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;001&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.18&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;002&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.28&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;003&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.38&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;004&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;11,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.48&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;005&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.58&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;006&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;13,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.68&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;007&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;14,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.78&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;008&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;15,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.88&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;009&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;16,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.98&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;010&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;17,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1.08&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonding curves are a newer concept and their implementations are improving thanks to the collaborative nature of decentralized finance. In support of fostering innovation and our commitment to ongoing improvement, all contracts are open source for auditing by anyone who’d would like to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full details of the Octoken bonding curve distribution and decentralized exchange allocation of the OCTO governance token are &lt;a href=&quot;/project/token&quot;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonding curve summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allocation of 125,000 OCTO for bonding curve sale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Equates to 15.625% of total supply with 800,000 hard cap.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starting 14 September 2020 at 00:00 UTC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ending when allocation sold out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initial price of $0.18&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Denominated in USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bonding curve in...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Governance Token Mechanisms for Octoken Holders</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/gov-token-mech" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Governance Token Mechanisms for Octoken Holders" /><published>2020-08-19T10:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-19T10:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/gov-token-mech</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/gov-token-mech">&lt;p&gt;The OCTO governance token is an essential part of the OctoFi ecosystem and is designed to foster the creation of decentralized finance &lt;s&gt;oracles&lt;/s&gt; tentacles. Absolute openness and transparency are the underlying principles through which the Octoken Project will equip stakeholders to support the wider community in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DeFi’s integrity depends on reliable data, much of which is provided by oracles and related infrastructure. The systems comprising OctoFi are governed through the OCTO governance token otherwise known as — ‘Octoken’ — intended to be held by a decentralized community of ‘Octonauts’ who are incentivized to govern efficiently and effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OctoFi is dedicated to supporting the emergence of a user-owned financial ecosystem whose best interests are well aligned. In order to achieve the best possible distribution of ownership, OCTO governance tokens shall be disbursed through various mechanisms. As explained in greater detail throughout the Octoken project page, the bonding curve is step one, but let’s take a look at the broader picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;octoken-allocations&quot;&gt;Octoken allocations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The total 800,000 OCTO supply is allocated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonding curve:&lt;/strong&gt; 125,000 OCTO for public sale commencing 14 September 2020 at 00:00 UTC as per the &lt;a href=&quot;/project/token&quot;&gt;full details provided&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest program:&lt;/strong&gt; 200,000 OCTO split equally between interest yielding contract and airdrop, both reserved for private and public sale investors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early backers:&lt;/strong&gt; 200,000 OCTO among small strategic cohort gathered during inception to ensure best possible deployment and transition.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project reserve:&lt;/strong&gt; 275,000 OCTO assigned to transparent project fund for allocation by governance token holders pending decisions made on subsequent DAO proposals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;octoken-distribution-mechanisms&quot;&gt;Octoken distribution mechanisms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OctoFi will utilize a number of governance distribution mechanisms to begin decentralizing from day one, including the initial bonding curve distribution, incentives for long term holders, ecosystem utilization, participation in governance, and funding of project improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-octoken-project&quot;&gt;1. Octoken project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OCTO governance tokens will be distributed through a bonding curve sale that commences 14 September 2020 at 00:00 UTC. A total of 125,000 tokens will be made available to participants and we welcome those who support the development of the DeFi ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By distributing governance in such a way, token bonding curves provide fairness and transparency. They are a sustainable way of striking a balance between the team and project supporters, to hold everyone accountable in the best interests of the community. It is critical to the project that early adopters are incentivized to foster a supportive environment and as such, longevity for the governance token’s utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-aquafarm-project&quot;&gt;2. Aquafarm project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OctoFi’s interest (and airdrop) program provides an attractive incentive scheme for holding governance tokens for 3, 6, and 12 month runtimes. Our own smart contract, and furthermore additional lending solutions, will provide the yield required for what we are calling Aquafarming. While the interest program allocation is specified, the potential for developing further yield bearing apps for OCTO holders is within reach in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-tentacles-project&quot;&gt;3. Tentacles project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralized finance &lt;s&gt;oracles&lt;/s&gt; tentacles are the core component of the OctoFi ecosystem. All Octonauts, regardless of holdings, are encouraged to participate in the various applications associated with their OCTO tokens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a community we are committed to advancing an open and transparent standard for data oracles that are truly owned and operated by token holders. As part of the Tentacles platform, further token distributions are associated with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remuneration for sourcing and provisioning data collection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Funding development resources and platform support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gaining access to live data feeds and API marketplace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;octoken-governance-functions&quot;&gt;Octoken governance functions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary use-case afforded by project supporters will be the foundational governance decisions. During early stages, OCTO governance tokens shall be used for the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Participating in voting to settle governance decisions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verifying data tentacles and support systems with staking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reminder:&lt;/strong&gt; the Octoken bonding curve distribution and decentralized exchange allocation of the OCTO governance token commences 14 September 2020 — &lt;a href=&quot;/project/token&quot;&gt;full details on the project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The OCTO governance token is an essential part of the OctoFi ecosystem and is designed to foster the creation of decentralized finance oracles tentacles. Absolute openness and transparency are the underlying principles through which the Octoken Project will equip stakeholders to support the wider community in general.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Infrastructure for Decentralized Finance with Tentacles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/defi-infra" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infrastructure for Decentralized Finance with Tentacles" /><published>2020-08-16T10:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-16T10:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/defi-infra</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/defi-infra">&lt;p&gt;We are in a time of unprecedented change and Ethereans the world over have risen to the challenge. As financial institutions refuse to act in the best interests of the people, Decentralized Finance (DeFi) is transforming legacy products into permissionless protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the depths of crypto winter, projects such as Synthetix, Compound, and many more have grown at an exponential rate. During their meteoric rise the need for essential infrastructure has come to the forefront and the market has responded, with support for projects delivering critical services that support DeFi’s ever changing technology landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As new blockchain use-cases emerge from DeFi, project teams must rise to the challenge in creating the ‘money legos’ that make truly decentralized applications possible. Unlike the centralized equivalents who rely on a select few, the burgeoning DeFi industry has its own unique set of requirements and constraints when it comes to third party service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;only-as-good-as-those-on-which-you-depend&quot;&gt;Only as good as those on which you depend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to composability, many platforms face problems regarding interdependence on other services. Great strides are being made to address concerns around transparency and auditability of external solutions, but individual users are still exposed to risks stemming from ambiguity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data oracles aim to provide accurate and dependable data for a broadening range of applications, but concerns around how they source and process data are yet to be addressed. Inconsistencies lead to exploits by bad actors and while strong competition within each sector provides assurance that these risks will be mitigated, their success depends on much more than just quality, accessibility, and auditability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the center of these concerns is centralization. We understand that innovators must forgo decentralization to some degree in certain cases, but resisting the easy route is critical if we are to succeed. The DeFi space moves quickly, obsolescence is always on the horizon, and the inherent permissionless-ness is attracting competent technologists at an ever increasing rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trust-undermines-defis-potential&quot;&gt;Trust undermines DeFi’s potential&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thought leaders within the broader cryptocurrency community have explored the importance of decentralization across the entire stack of an application. While more and more people are interacting with permissionless systems, whether these systems are in fact trustless is increasingly scrutinized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These concerns are exacerbated by the tendency for value locked to move between protocols so erratically. After all, these human actions are often driven by emotions rather than logic, and such fear, uncertainty, and doubt can force users to make irrational decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who’ve been in the crypto space long enough, it’s widely accepted that choosing your sources wisely and widely, is essential for the simple fact that individual data sources are more likely manipulated. We can learn from the mistakes of those who’ve been burned by having too much trust in a single entity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There should be no single points of failure when we are pioneering decentralized technologies and intermediary risks should be mitigated however possible in order to legitimize DeFi. Centralized entities require trust, are easily corrupted, and ensuring users can better spread risks associated with early adoption should be a core focus of the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introducing-octofi&quot;&gt;Introducing OctoFi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OctoFi is a next generation open source platform providing decentralized finance oracles tentacles for DeFi. We believe that the term ‘oracle’ itself implies unreasonable dependence on a single source of truth. In most cases, an oracle is viewed as singular, and while we appreciate their importance, we foresee the existence of many, all of which are auditable against one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the decentralized finance world, individuals shall act as proxies to an aggregation of oracular data sources, in order to optimize their own participation and interaction with an ever expanding landscape of protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OctoFi users will benefit from an ‘octomized’ structure whereby ‘tentacles’ connect them with various applications, while leveraging truly open and transparent infrastructure. Stakeholders will play an important role in data validation while pioneering a new frontier of community governance for long term, sustainable adaptability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;octoken---where-it-all-begins&quot;&gt;Octoken - where it all begins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OctoFi infrastructure is designed for frictionless oversight by incentivised stakeholders who share in its best interests. Data sourcing, provisioning, verification, quality assurance, storage, and consumption, all utilise the such tokenomics for effective governance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OCTO governance tokens are essential to:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Participating in voting to settle governance decisions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remuneration for sourcing and provisioning data collection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verifying data tentacles and support systems with staking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Funding development resources and platform support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gaining access to live data feeds and API marketplace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our flagship project, &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/token&quot;&gt;Octoken&lt;/a&gt;, includes bonding curve distribution and decentralized exchange allocation of the OCTO governance token commencing 14 September 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are in a time of unprecedented change and Ethereans the world over have risen to the challenge. As financial institutions refuse to act in the best interests of the people, Decentralized Finance (DeFi) is transforming legacy products into permissionless protocols.</summary></entry></feed>